<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>[RF] Permafrost (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.RFPermafrost</packageId>
  <author>Rainbeau Flambe</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/RFPermafrost</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies />
  <loadAfter />
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/buuPQel.png[/img]
Update of Rainbeau Flambes mod https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1540322147
based on the 1.1-1.3 version by trooperSmith1 https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2021524321

[img]https://i.imgur.com/pufA0kM.png[/img]

[table]
    [tr][td][url=https://dsc.gg/mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td] [td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/RFPermafrost][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
    [tr]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/WjDSfUn.png[/img][/td]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/6KqTKks.png[/img][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]
	
[img]https://i.imgur.com/Z4GOv8H.png[/img]
[b]"Permafrost," as you'd probably guess, adds a new biome to the game. Permafrost exists on the border between tundra and ice sheets. The ground is permanently frozen, and much of it is covered in ice, but unlike the ice on ice sheets, the ground ice here is at most a few meters, rather than kilometers, thick. There is little vegetation beyond scrub brush, and few animals.

Additionally, the mod also allows water to freeze. This means that lakes, rivers and marshes in any biome will slowly ice over when the temperature drops below freezing, and only thaw again when the temperature rises. It also means that ground ice in permafrost biomes will (very) slowly advance and retreat with temperature changes. (If you don't like this feature, it can be disabled in the mod's "options" menu.)

Note that if you have a fishing spot (whether from my own "Fishing" mod, "Thanks for All the Fish," or "ZARS Simple Fish") located on a water tile that freezes, the fishing spot will be destroyed. You can't fish through ice. Fishing piers from "FishIndustry" are not impacted, though, and neither are shellfish traps from "Fishing," since they're actual buildings with material costs.

- Rainbeau Flambe (dburgdorf)[/b]

[h1][b][u]Compatibility:[/u][/b][/h1]

I wouldn't expect this mod to conflict with any other mods. 

"Permafrost" can safely be added to a game in progress, though obviously, it won't add new biomes to an already-generated map. Trying to remove the mod from a game in progress, however, would be ill-advised.

[h1][b][u]License:[/u][/b][/h1]

If you're a modpack maker and want to include "Permafrost" in your pack, or if you're a modder and want to use it as the basis of a derivative mod, please feel free to do so. I ask only that you let me know about it. 

If you have any (helpful) suggestions for improvement, please let me know!

[hr]
Extra info from the 1.1-1.3 updated version:
I have updated Permafrost for both 1.1 and 1.2, as well as making some minor changes and adding compatibility. Flowing water now freezes at a lower temperature than still water (ponds and marshes), and for both types there are a range of temperatures at which both new ice will form, and existing ice will melt, making ice formation and thawing much more dynamic and interesting.

Highly recommended that you also use a mod like [XND] Watermill Tweaks (Continued) to reduce watermill power output during winter and when it is particularly cold.
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2055956298

Compatibility for Vanilla Fishing Expanded has been added
Compatible with Terraform Rimworld (based on preliminary testing)
Compatible with Dub's Bad Hygiene with his next update (10/10/20)


[img]https://i.imgur.com/PwoNOj4.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] or the standalone [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2873415404]Uploader[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[*] Use [url=https://github.com/RimSort/RimSort/releases/latest]RimSort[/url] to sort your mods
[/list]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/3027775257][img]https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/emipa606/RFPermafrost?label=latest%20version&amp;style=plastic&amp;color=9f1111&amp;labelColor=black[/img][/url]</description>
  <modIconPath IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">ModIcon/RFPermafrost</modIconPath>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.5.0</modVersion>
</ModMetaData>